there's a lot of discussions going on on
capitol hill right now domestic politics
there's big heat happening the democrats
are arguing or are they really arguing
over the budget bill my name is garland
nixon
and i'm john kiriakou
let's talk
[Music]
you know john when it comes to congress
i don't know if i'm in a reality zone or
i don't know if i've gone down the
conspiracy theorist zone
but i'm at a point where i just don't
believe the things that i see anymore
and i tell you
and i'll give you
explain
so i'm watching what appears to be a
battle on capitol hill and what i'm told
is it's the moderate democrats against
the they use different names the
progressives the liberals the left flank
right and that they're battling over
these bills and that people really
believe in what they're saying and in
the back of my mind i keep thinking it's
kabuki theater
they got a deal worked out and it's not
what they're telling us john tell me am
i i mean what let me put you like this
you have worked on capitol hill you work
for the senate foreign intelligence
committee give me give us your insider
information am i out in la la land or is
there any any reality under my feet left
no you you are exactly right you know
i'm i'm embarrassed to even say that
that i got a master's degree in
legislative affairs because i so badly
wanted to work on capitol hill and i've
worked on both the house side and the
senate side and i can tell you that the
entire system is broken with that said
it's broken in a way
that
now individual members of congress
really don't have any say in any of this
legislation
everything rests in the offices of the
majority leader of the senate and the
speaker of the house it's been like this
since the mid 1990s when newt gingrich
became speaker
on the house side the way things used to
work is that anybody could propose
legislation and it would be referred to
the appropriate committee and then the
chairman of that committee was really
the the power right you had to convince
the chairman that this legislation was
worthwhile and then if it passed
committee it went to the rules committee
the rules committee was the most
powerful committee on capitol hill and
they decided whether or not your
legislation got a floor vote well newt
gingrich changed all that in the 1990s
and now literally everything has to go
through the office of the speaker well
subsequent speakers never change that
because who wants to give up power and
authority right
so now if you want something passed into
law nancy has to say it's okay
in fact a member of congress
said that to me just six months ago i
said to him
hey this whistleblower protection
legislation that you had was really
great what happened was it killed in
committee and he said oh nancy said i
couldn't do it those were his exact
words
nancy said i couldn't do it well that's
how every piece of legislation is so now
when i see in politico or on cnn or
wherever
that there's this fight between the
moderates and the progressives and that
pelosi had to delay a vote because she's
trying to placate the liberals that's
nonsense
they vote yes if she tells them to vote
yes and they vote on whatever it is she
tells them to vote on and the situation
is almost exactly the same in the senate
50 50 believe it or not is a majority
and so
you know if chuck schumer wants to push
this of course he would have to deal
with the uh the uh uh you know
republicans slowing things down with the
filibuster but
you know if they want to vote on this
they can have their vote
so and and yeah and so when i hear and
and i feel like people are like so
bamboozled because here is the setup to
me and that is and and and this pushes
the whole you know argument that um this
i i feel like they're doing things to
support false narratives right so the
narrative is congress works the way it
used to with committees and you know the
power remember charlie rangel was in
charge of the way he's going commission
how powerful he was and all these things
there's power but
if that were true this whole discussion
about christian cinema and joe manchin
being oh my gosh they're tough if only
we could get through them you know if
only we could get those guys but you
know they're in the way and blah blah
blah so now we've got like all of the
the the blue no matter who people right
the die hard true believing democrats
are all furious at joe manchin and
christian cinema because certainly
before if you remember it was a senate
parliament parliamentarian how they
bought that foolishness but
it's not biden
it's not the ruling elite or the
oligarchs that are that are supporting
them it's not nancy pelosi it's not none
of them somehow we're supposed to
believe that some schmuck from west
virginia and arizona can hold up the
entire u.s empire when it wants to do
something and that is it's so laughable
what is really sad to me though is that
i'm watching people buy into that absurd
scenario in my opinion
yes these two people they're stalking
horses they're being used and i don't
mean used in a way that they don't know
it i mean they're being used as a
propaganda tool to pretend that this
thing is really a legitimate process
when really it's a fraud
oh you're totally right i
i hate for us to sit here and agree with
one another but i'm gonna sit here and
agree with you you're exactly right you
know there used to be senators like uh
well for example there was a guy from
wisconsin named william proxmeyer
and bill proxmeyer had a reputation of
being a liberal democrat he actually
took the seat that had been held by joe
mccarthy so he was 180 degree difference
from joe mccarthy but the thing about
proxmeyer is
he used to give out this uh this award
um it was like for for you know worst
bureaucrat in government kind of award
and he would always give it to uh to
somebody in dod
because they would always try to
inflate their budgets or hide the covert
budget within the dod budget and he
would always catch them you know he
would give an award to the dod office
that was spending two million dollars to
study the sex habits of goldfish for
example
so um but the thing about proxmyer why
why we need a bill proxmyer in these
days
is that prox meyer if he had an
objection to government spending
it was to all government spending and
what made me think of proxmyer today was
uh
was a statement that joe manchin made
this morning
uh in which he said there's there's
nothing progressive about spending 1.5
trillion dollars right
well
listen we're happy to spend a trillion
dollars on defense
we're happy to to spend more money than
the next eight largest countries
combined
on defense where the heck was joe
manchin when they were passing the
defense budget
right if if now all of a sudden you
don't want to you don't want to spend
any money
because it's breaking the bank where
were you when they were talking about a
trillion dollar
defense budget and nobody bothered to
object on the floor of the senate where
were you
so i'm just not buying it i think you're
right garland on on the house side
uh this is kabuki theater
on the senate side uh they're gonna have
to placate
cinema and mansion at least
in public i do have a a question though
for you if i could ask a question sure
i've been watching kristen or kirsten
cinema
for for weeks now
and i don't understand her angle
uh it's gotten so bad that today
politico ran an article saying that
there are some
well-known arizona progressives who are
thinking of running against her in the
democratic primary you know it's one
thing to be joe manchin right and to
sort of you know pretend to be
conservative because you're from west
virginia and you have to pretend it
becomes to be conservative but kristen
cinema doesn't need to pretend to be
conservative i think she legitimately is
conservative she just happens to have a
d after her name so what do you think
her goal here is
well you know when i look at chris
christie and kristen cinema i i don't
see you know when you see the power
players on um
you know on uh um
capitol hill you know you see them as
just craving players in a game but you
feel as though they're smart but evil
you know what i mean like they're pretty
sharp they understand the game they can
play 3d chess but they're you know sure
ted cruz went to harvard law school
you know a machiavellian narcissistic
all that kind of stuff right exactly
to me when i see a kristen cinema i
don't see her as a 3d chess playing
person so i don't see her as one of
these i'll put it this way the evil
intellectual the craven narcissistic
really smart person who's up to no good
i see her as a person who's trying to
play the game based on the way she sees
things but i don't
i'll just put it this way i don't see
her as being as sharp as the other
people because one of the things about a
good politician is they can hide they
got a poker face you don't know who they
are you don't know what they're up to
you can't figure them out or if you
think you've got them figured about
they'd like to say about sharks you know
as soon as you think you got them
figured out they do something different
and that's so that then i don't see her
as a 3d chess player i see her as kind
of a schmuck in there who doesn't know
what the hell she's doing she's going to
piss she doesn't understand the balance
right between
um
look playing the game when you're on
capitol hill
and bamboozling
your people at home to believe that
you're bringing home the bacon at the
same time there's a careful game that
these people are really good at playing
where they screw the people at home they
give everything to the billionaires wall
street the usual but they can come home
with a grin on their face and now have a
little something for them or at least
they can hide when they're doing their
dirt or they will um count the votes and
they won't they'll be completely against
the bill but they'll vote for it because
they know it's going to pass anyway or
the opposite you know what i mean so
they strategically use their votes to
make it appear like they're supporting
things or opposing things that they
don't okay that's all a good game
and it keeps your people at home happy
they keep voting you in you keep
screwing i mean getting richer i don't
see cinema as a person that that's the
big thing i'll say she's not real sharp
in that she understands that and she can
maintain that balance and that's going
to get her ass thrown out back in
arizona one of our uh one of our viewers
cannabinated fantasy makes an important
point here um i don't know if
cannabinated is a man or a woman but
cannabinated says the goal is to
overshadow the real division and the
party and group the center i think
there's something to that you know back
in the day i mean really as as recently
as the 1980s you had conservative
democrats in the senate you had liberal
republicans in the senate and the job of
a party whip was almost impossible
because rather than being grouped by
party people were more
commonly grouped by ideology
that's why so many democrats voted
against the civil rights act and the
voting rights act because they were
southern conservatives they were
old-school dixiecrats and that's why all
the liberal republicans
like
mac matthias from maryland and uh
senator uh brooke from massachusetts i
remember phil bradley he was one yeah
and they and they were they were
unabashed liberals even though they were
members of the republican party
um it's not like that anymore
and
things are so closely divided that the
job of the whip is paramount you know
it's not an accident that
that they use the word whip because you
have to whip votes into line it comes
from the 18th century right um
i think that's we have now we have
something that's so
deeply divided ideologically
that it's become unworkable
yeah now here's something i'm going to
i'm going to share with you i mean
you're familiar with uh tom massey
yes indeed from kentucky yes all right
so here's an article massey gop rep
lashes aipac for foreign interference
after iron dome vote attack so what
happened so he opposed the iron dome now
for those of you who don't know he's a
libertarian guy there's things i don't
agree with him on i will say one thing
about a lot of libertarians i can
disagree with them strongly in economic
issues some other issues but
they believe in what they believe in
yeah they do they tend to have a moral
center whether you
agree with it or not and they stand for
what they believe in so massey voted
against the um the billion dollars in
funding and that's what he said it's
extreme to bankrupt our country and put
future generations of americans and hawk
the debtors well whether you get you
know we could have all kind of talk
about where we spend money and waste
money on f35s but what you can't say is
that tom massey votes for that stuff
because he votes against all of it all
the time so what happens
apac comes after him yeah they start
running ads online
he's anti-semitic
yes you know what's interesting about
that
we were told for years that facebook
page with pages with buff bernie or
puppies or something from some um
internet research agency in russia that
that was that the whole election was
turned because of some facebook groups
with things that were really
nominally related to the election and
and even social issues at best right
right but
aipac can if it's if it's a a selected
okay country aipac could do it saudi
arabia could probably certain countries
could get away with it right certain um
quote allies could get away with it can
do anything and they want to jim
benjamin netanyahu came to congress and
and preached against the sitting
president yes and his party and gotta
get away with it but what we're told is
uh the iranians sent an email to some
people in florida which is just i don't
know if you remember that email and it
said we know who you're voting for we're
the proud boys i mean it was so childish
to think that any
international um uh uh um intelligence
agency would write like a first grade
email and send it to people and say
that's gonna change the election that
was preposterous but this is real stuff
what are your thoughts on that john
oh man you know this is first of all i i
know congressman massey not very well
but we have a mutual friend and we went
to a baseball game together and this is
a guy who really believes in what he
believes in
none of this is for the media it's not
for you know
nationwide consumption the guy has very
strongly held beliefs and and let's talk
about iron dome for one second one thing
that most americans don't know iron dome
is the is the missile system that is
supposed to protect israel from
terrorist missile attacks but let's look
at iron dome iron dome was created and
developed by
uh uh technology and defense contractor
in israel that was funded it was
financed by the israeli knesset it was a
quasi-governmental defense contractor
and then the government spun it off and
made it private and when they did that
they said oh my gosh iron dome is really
really important but it's just too
expensive we can't afford it so we
should ask congress to pay us for it
and so without even so much as a debate
congress decided to fund the iron dome
well listen
it's not my problem if the israelis
can't afford their own missile system
then what they need to do is raise taxes
so they can afford it it shouldn't be up
to me or up to you to protect israel
from missiles
right
well
massey is one of the very very few
people in congress with the guts to
stand up and actually say that
and so the israelis
arguably interfered
in domestic american politics
by taking issue with that
just like they interfered repeatedly
when benjamin netanyahu was the prime
minister and he would make regular
trips to the united states to speak
before congress
now that last trip that he made when
obama was president
that you just referred to
he came here and in great violation of
protocol
did not make an appointment or even seek
an appointment to see the president of
the united states
and then he gave
a speech to a joint session of congress
invited by the republican party
in which he criticized a sitting
president
and made an endorsement
in the u.s presidential election
that is wrong with a capital w it might
have even been illegal
and
it's unacceptable if you're an american
citizen and an american voter
absolutely next article it's a
responsible state craft responsible
statecraft's interest very interesting
john it's um
you know a website it's a it's the
funded i think it's under the quincy
institute and the quincy institute's
interesting because it's funded by you
know the soros's and the koch brothers
of the world so few people trust it and
in reading it here's what i'll say
you'll find some stuff in there that's
written that's pretty good
and you'll find some other stuff that's
crap and what i mean is this you know
how there are people that argue that
they're the realists in washington the
infamous realist but the realists are
basically what they're saying is i'm
going to go
with the narrative of the washington
consensus the neocon narrative and i'm
gonna give you a light version of that
and i'm gonna put a smile on that and
that's what you get often from the
responsible statecraft but it's worth
reading because other times you will get
some pretty good stuff what are your
thoughts
yes we we have to be very careful of
groups like this um
by account of the washington post there
are more than 1200 if you can imagine
organizations in washington dc alone or
in the washington dc area that describe
themselves as think tanks
it's almost impossible to know who
finances them
but we need to know who finances them so
that we can use our own critical
thinking skills to decide if we should
believe them if they take if they take
you know
positions that are that are workable for
example or if they're answering to
something like one of the defense
contractors i'll give you a quick
example um someone to whom i used to be
very very close uh worked for a major
fortune 100 defense contractor and she
was in charge of doling out about 200
000 dollars in donations to uh think
tanks that you know thought the right
way and wrote the right kinds of
articles
she went to see one of these think tanks
and it's a it's a household name right
and um decided that they weren't
pro defense contractor enough
and so the next year she gave the 200
000 to
the other guy who was going to pander to
the defense contractors we'll multiply
that by every defense contractor in
america right and that's where these
stupid and crazy foreign policy ideas
come from
so this one is interesting arms biz
swirls around house votes blocking
pentagon uh cuts many of those who
opposed amendments to reign in
department of defense's bloated coffers
have been underwritten by weapons
industries they go on with some numbers
and um
for instance mark pocon an aoc led an
amendment that would have cut the the
pentagon's approved uh uh approval line
by 10
and then barbara lee and sarah jacobs
would have eliminated the entire 23.9
billion increase right
well they get down to um on lobbying
alone arms profiters spent 103.96
million
in 2020.
um in the 2020 election cycle they
poured 15 million 584 937 into house
members
not a single gop lawmaker supported
either amendment among democrats an
overwhelming majority voted against the
the the
24.9 billion increase however only 86
voted to reduce the pentagon budget by
10 so they play games so that when they
know something won't pass they'll vote
against it and then once it gets to the
to the floor or the house or the senate
they'll vote present they'll vote
against it they'll get out of the way
they'll play games and and they'll
actually sit around
because i was friends you know i guess i
used to work with mr conyers office and
i have a lot of friends that were around
and staffers where they would sit around
and they would look at a vote and they'd
say we got enough votes here the other
people who's running
well this guy's not running you're not
running for six years you can vote for
it what about you what you're running
what's your district well you don't have
to and it wasn't that the members of
congress sat around based on their
belief in their heart in their right no
they sat around determining who could
and couldn't vote for it based on who
needed to get re-elected who needed to
stay friends what what special interest
groups they had that were pressuring
them from home and things like that this
thing's a fraud yeah mr smith goes to
washington it ain't i i would recommend
you know
if you can stand the cynicism of
watching house of cards on netflix um it
it's one of the most cynical shows i've
ever watched in my life and the reason
why i couldn't tear myself away from it
is because that's how washington
actually is you're not lying garland
when you say that that you are generally
told how to vote and it's based on when
you're coming up for re-election and how
much money you took from
lobbyists
that's how they calculate these things
you know
frequently when members of congress
announce their retirement and usually
in this case it's members of the senate
they'll say that they're retiring
because the system is broken well this
is what they're talking about the story
that you just told is what they're
talking about they are not free to vote
their consciences they are not free to
vote based on what's best for the for
the country or even what's best for the
people in their state
they have to vote the way their
leadership tells them to vote
and that's based on what the lobbyists
say i'll add one more thing when i was
on the senate foreign relations
committee staff
um
senator john kerry that then senator
john kerry was the chairman and he came
in one day and told us that
that we were going to start taking part
in the debate on um
carbon
offsets okay it was only tangentially a
foreign affairs issue but he was the
chairman and he was also on the finance
committee which was doing carbon offsets
so we had to do what he told us to do
and i said to my to my boss he was the
staff director i said man i don't know
anything about carbon offsets i i'm
happy to talk about yemen
or
afghanistan but carbon offsets and he
said oh don't worry about it he said the
lobbyists are going to do all the work
well the very next day
these strangers started coming into our
office they took over most of the desks
and they would just sit there log on to
the system and start writing and i said
to him
who are these people
and he said oh these are the lobbyists
they're writing the carbon offset bill
for us
that's the way capitol hill works you
know when um
uh one of the one of the uh things that
has helped me to be able to you know be
on a number of different shows you know
i've got my show in in dc and now i've
got a show in los angeles and one of the
things that helps me is um i have made
of some predictions that have been that
have that have worked a lot of good
predictions and probably you know i
predicted trump would win a particular
but a lot of stuff that worked out right
and people like wow that's good and i'm
like it's my cynicism yeah it's just my
cynicism that's right i'm not
nostradamus i'm just so cynical that i'm
like yeah that's a bunch of bull crap uh
it's probably gonna go this way and one
of the things was obamacare
when the republicans you know trump came
in and everybody's like oh the
republicans are going to kill obamacare
i said it ain't happening
not happened and they said why i said
let me give you a couple reasons i can
give you numerous one being one of the
things that obamacare does is they hand
out literally billions and billions of
dollars just write checks and go write
to
corporations here you go how many people
you got you got a bunch of people yeah
here's seven billion i said number one
the healthcare corporations ain't gonna
stop getting those for that free money
number two
the red states were where the most
people were in obamacare yes so if they
killed obamacare today
the problem was they had implied to
their people obamacare is bad which i
got lots of issues with it therefore the
implication is if we get rid of it we're
going to give you something better
but they didn't and they weren't going
to so i said if they get rid of
obamacare their people in their states
are going to look at them and say hooray
you got rid of obamacare now we're
really going to have it made what do you
got for us and they had nothing i said
they ain't getting rid of obamacare
there's no way that's going to happen
well here's the thing that's interesting
and this is a perfect example we're
talking about it all goes down to this
big theater and in the end the one guy
john mccain who's not running again
conveniently the guy who's 80 freaking
years old and has already announced he's
not running again yeah and he's dying of
cancer he's dying of cancer he comes in
at the last minute to save obamacare and
these republicans were like oh john
mccain stabbed us in the back again so
they were mad at him the democrats were
like that john mccain gotta love him
yeah he'll cross and i'm like
you guys didn't can't really you know i
just
doing this that people can't see that
they've been schnooked again
it's so true
you know i remember
you remember how the mantra for the
republicans was repeal and replace
repeal and replace okay well you guys
controlled the white house the house and
the senate and you couldn't repeal and
replace
and
it never occurred to anybody that maybe
they should actually come up with an
alternative that they could use to
replace obamacare once it was repealed i
remember when donald trump was first
elected he was talking a lot about
trumpcare that was supposed to be the
plan to replace obamacare even though
nobody really knew what trumpcare meant
and certainly nothing had been written
down on paper
and i remember watching one of the
broadcast networks news shows abc cbs
whatever it was and there was a woman
from um arkansas and she was crying
with thanks because her son had cancer
and they had no insurance but they went
to this website and they got the
insurance and
he had his cancer treatment and she was
crying thank you president trump thank
you
and then finally said somebody said or
it was the reporter he said well you
know that that's obamacare right and she
said no
obamacare was repealed and replaced this
is trumpcare and the reporter said no it
wasn't repealed and replaced and there's
never been a vote on anything called
trumpcare
but a lot of people were confused
that's a long way of saying
your account is
indeed correct
this stuff is all pre-ordained it's all
written
yeah and so as going and going forth
here's the way i look at it and this is
what i wear what i really think is the
key i'm going to give you what i think
is the key to you know right now they've
got supposedly a trillion and a half a
trillion dollar infrastructure which is
really only 550 billion the other is
being moved up but that's another story
right three and a point five trillion
supposedly on this or that here's what i
think
then it's not happening and here's why
in order to do this and here's the key
to me
the trump tax cuts
donald trump's tax cuts were
let me tell you people are like i hate
the neoliberal donald trump was the
biggest neoliberal we've ever seen i
mean you couldn't be more of a
neoliberal than trump i mean those those
those tax cuts you talk about neoliberal
right
so
these the trump tax cuts gave more money
than anyone in history has ever given to
the rich at the same time so he gives
these corporations the rich people get
these gigantic tax cuts now
joe biden even mentioned it in order to
do this three and a half plus another
trillion we're up to getting 5 trillion
you're gonna have to dig in to the trump
tax cut some of them are going to have
to go
and the billionaire donors who own the
republicans and the democrats do not
want to see a dime of the trump tax cuts
gone and they will have their way so
ultimately because the trump tax cuts
have to do this have to be part of it if
they can they'll figure out how much of
this can go without cutting back into
their trump that's all it's really about
all this stuff rest of this talk about
whether or not they can get it that's
window dressing the billionaires are
sitting there saying you ain't cutting
it now what they may do and i've heard
talk of this they may raise the gas tax
10 cent a mile and soak the average
schmuck so now what will they do the
trump tax cuts are there the
billionaires will keep it everything and
if anything happens they're going to
soak the working class even more and but
the forget this whole big thing if a
penny has to come out of the trump tax
cuts it's all going to die you know the
theodore roosevelt said that a person's
tax should be based on his ability to
pay
um
we used to talk about progressive
taxation in this country we used to be
proud
for many years of the progressive
taxation system that we had in this
country it fell apart under ronald
reagan and it's gotten worse and worse
and worse
we need attacks on the very rich
we know that it won't hurt them they
won't even notice it
uh but these regressive taxes
like increasing the gas tax
hurt the people
who are the least able
to withstand the hit
we've we've gotta we've got to go back
you know the republicans always say we
need to go back to the 50s right to the
good old days when everything was great
and everybody was getting along okay you
know what on taxation let's go back to
the 50s where we've got a a top taxation
rate of you know 90 or whatever it was
because then we had balanced budgets
right and people could could work and
save and buy a house and do better than
their parents did and provide for their
children and and have their children go
to college but we've put ourselves in a
position now with these regressive taxes
where we've just screwed ourselves and
the next generation
let me tell you a quick story we'll only
be here a few more minutes but let me
tell you a quick story a quick story
about something about domestic politics
that i learned accidentally when i first
retired from law enforcement i had my
bunch of insurance licenses and i was
selling life insurance home uh health
insurance etc right
and there's something called that i
found out later i found it's a scam but
it's called social security for excuse
me medicare
uh not improvement advanced medicare
plus medicare
uh i can't think of the name of it but
but they're these private medicare plans
they privatized a certain part of
medicare medicare advantage plans
okay and so what i found out was a
person has medicare i had my license i
could go some people you could give it
to him you have medicare here you sign
up for this plan it kind of takes you
out of medicare and puts you into this
kind of hmo where you can get a few
extra things but there's other things
you can't get right so it's an
alternative to medicare right
and these other companies administer it
so there was this company called care
something or other right so i get in
there and they're like look here's what
happens garland you go to a person who
has medicare you convince them they sign
up for this you get 300 bucks for
everybody that signs up i'm like oh okay
so i went and started signing people up
300 bucks a person i remember i went in
one place like this senior home 18
people signed up one afternoon when i'm
like hey this is works but after a while
i got out of it i had a lot of issues
with it here's what i'm getting at
so this company that this company i find
out that these companies a whole bunch
of companies will go to medicare when
this opens up and they will bid and they
will try to get the contract to do this
because it's basically a license to
print money signing up medicare people
for free and you get money for the
government
how easy does that get
i start looking into this company and i
find this
so this company goes to you know it
opens up they apply they end up being i
don't know if it was a lottery or
whatever but they get a contract from
medicare so now they're guaranteed to
make money
as soon as they do that goldman sachs
bought them
oh my god and i find out i'm working for
goldman sachs and here's what i in
looking into the deeper here's what i
found out
for all of this goldman sachs and these
big corporations we got to stop the
government we got to keep the government
off of our back do you know how much
money goldman sachs makes in government
contracts if you have a company john if
you and i start a company tomorrow and
we go get a a a a a government contract
and that government contract will pay us
50 million dollars and we know we got it
all figured out we're going to make 50
million dollars in um
over 10 years five years whatever right
goldman sachs will come up and say i'll
give you 30 right now up front no
questions asked they'll buy it for the
extra so they go buy companies to get um
government contracts so the bottom line
is for all of this talk of their opposed
to government government regulations
these same same banks and corporations
are getting rich off of government
contracts and let me add this
don't you think old cynical garland i
don't have to guess on this don't you
think if goldman sachs has companies
that are vying for contracts whether
it's health and health and human
services medicare medicaid services
whatever that they have the wherewithal
to influence legislators to ensure that
their companies get those contracts and
get their contracts renewed oh yeah big
time
with a name like goldman sachs
or
city bank or you know any of these other
big ones these big wall street players
yeah they control their own destinies
that's it so i didn't realize that and
that's when i came to find out there are
all of these corporations that are you
think goldman sachs is a bank these
corporations have realized that's why
all of them moved their headquarters to
dc and northern virginia because they
realized they're like amazon's moving
their headquarters to northern virginia
wow they're doing that because it's a
good location no they're doing that
amazon just got a 10 billion dollar
contract as they say in africa the lion
stays close to the herd
that's so right well thanks a lot john
we've been on 37 minutes i think that's
long enough for a friday night don't you
well thanks everybody all right good
talking to you guys i want to thank uh
cannabinoid cannabinated fantasy i got
to say that's probably my favorite day
for today congressional gridlock enables
the maximum amount of interest to sway a
bill that is correct thanks a lot don't
forget everyone
share uh this video on all your social
media platforms make sure you subscribe
make sure you um uh click the little
bell and uh follow john and i and let
all your friends know that we john and i
are out regularly we're doing a lot of
fun videos thanks a lot peace we are out
good night